

Status: M.Sc. Digital Media, Scientific Employee

Fields: Software Engineering, Consulting, Scrum, Usability
Techs: Meteor, Javascript, Mongo, Bootstrap, Bash, Git, Webstorm

Activities: Global Game Jam, Open Source, Fitness

Bremen, Germany www.jankuester.com info@jankuester.com +49 176 *** *** ****

Summary

Digital media graduate with project experience in the field of technology based assessment. Currently working as IT Consultant at We4IT, Bremen in the field of IBM Notes Domino and XPages applications. Master studies focused on teams from different disciplines and cultural backgrounds on solutions for complex problems.

Experience

Scientific Employee / PhD Student - University of Bremen 2016 - present · Develop and evaluate the next generation learning management system with Meteor · Define a new level of software for classroom management based on an extensive nursing curriculum. IT Consultant for IBM XPages and Notes Domino - We4IT GmbH Bremen 2014 - 2016 · Realize projects in XPages and We4IT Aveedo, monitor project status, conduct reports · Implement the frontend for a BPMN compatible engine within We4IT Aveedo Scientific Employee / Software Development - University of Bremen 2012 - 2014 · Invented a flexible assessment framework, targeting industrial trainees · Supervised software development lifecycle, Recruited team members **Project Management Simulation Training** - Getoq Consulting 2011 / 11 · Performed a two-day project simulation from management perspective · Topics included customer contracts, change management, controlling, operational tasks Student Assistant / Programmer - otulea.uni-bremen.de 2010 - 2011 · Realized an online diagnosis platform for workforce literacy development (Flex) · Modeled software design, implemented various prototypes, conducted usability tests

Education	
Graduated as M.Sc. Digital Media - University of Bremen	2015 / 07
Master Thesis: Semi Automated Scoring in Technology Based Assessment Developed and evaluated an algorithm for semi automated scoring of spreadsheet data	
Master Project - PrIMA - University of Bremen	2012 - 2013
Co-Invented a touch table application for medical support, co-developed software (Java) Formed a scrum team, mainted project dev server (Debian), surveyed target audience	
Master Studies Digital Media - University of Bremen	2012 - 2015

- · Inter-cultural classes in English, covering special topics in computer science and design
- · Professionalized in research methods, software development and e-assessment

Semester Abroad - University of Melbourne

2009 - 2010

- · Mastered six months of study and trans-cultural experience in Melbourne, Australia
- · Finished machine programming, information visualization, professional essay writing